<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Azmi&#39;s Portfolio Website</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Azmi&#39;s Portfolio Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: US Yield Curve Inversion</title>
      <link>/projects/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project2/</guid>
      <description>Project 2: Yield Curve inversion
Every so often, we hear warnings from commentators on the “inverted yield curve” and its predictive power with respect to recessions. An explainer what a inverted yield curve is can be found here. If you’d rather listen to something, here is a great podcast from NPR on yield curve indicators
In addition, many articles and commentators think that, e.g., Yield curve inversion is viewed as a harbinger of recession.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Climate Change and Temperature Anomalies</title>
      <link>/projects/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project3/</guid>
      <description>Climate change and temperature anomalies If we wanted to study climate change, we can find data on the Combined Land-Surface Air and Sea-Surface Water Temperature Anomalies in the Northern Hemisphere at NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies. The tabular data of temperature anomalies can be found here
To define temperature anomalies you need to have a reference, or base, period which NASA clearly states that it is the period between 1951-1980.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: CDC COVID-19</title>
      <link>/projects/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project4/</guid>
      <description>Let us revisit the CDC Covid-19 Case Surveillance Data.
# file contains 11 variables and 3.66m rows and is well over 380Mb. # It will take time to download # URL link to CDC to download data url &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;https://data.cdc.gov/api/views/vbim-akqf/rows.csv?accessType=DOWNLOAD&amp;quot; covid_data &amp;lt;- vroom::vroom(url)%&amp;gt;% # If vroom::vroom(url) doesn&amp;#39;t work, use read_csv(url) clean_names() Given the data we have, I will produce two graphs that show death % rate:
by age group, sex, and whether the patient had co-morbidities or not by age group, sex, and whether the patient was admited to Intensive Care Unit (ICU) or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Lets play around with some Stocks!</title>
      <link>/projects/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project1/</guid>
      <description>Lets take a look at the NYSE #Downloading the data we need nyse &amp;lt;- read_csv(here::here(&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;nyse.csv&amp;quot;)) Lets see how the NYSE is made up #Grouping the companies in the NYSE by sector companies_per_sector &amp;lt;- nyse %&amp;gt;% group_by(sector) %&amp;gt;% summarise(count=count(sector)) %&amp;gt;% arrange(desc(count)) #Lets see what it looks like in a bar graph bar &amp;lt;- companies_per_sector %&amp;gt;% ggplot(aes(y=reorder(sector,count),x=count))+ geom_col()+ labs(y=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,x=&amp;quot;# of Companies&amp;quot;,title=&amp;quot;Companies in the NYSE&amp;quot;)+ theme_economist_white() bar   Now lets look at the Dow Jones Industrial Aveareg (DJIA) djia_url &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;https://en.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/projects/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/project5/</guid>
      <description>I was born and raised in Singapore where I spent the first twenty years of my life. Being from Singapore, I had to undergo two years of national service, which is compulsory for all male citizens. For my national service, I was enlisted into the Singapore Police Force where I served as a front line police officer and attended to “999” emergency cases from the public. Although it was compulsory, I enjoyed my time as a policeman and was eventually promoted to a sergeant due to my exemplary work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
